Emad Mohamed

Team Lead | Senior PHP Developer | Senior Backend PHP | Senior Full Stack | Senior Software Engineer

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/emad-mohamed-software-engineer/

Email: eng.emadmohamedphp@gmail.com

Phone: (+02) 01223872695

Website: https://emadmohdev.github.io/emad-mohamed-cv/

GitHub: https://github.com/EmadMohDev

Skype: emad.mohamed_edigits

Address: Giza -Egypt

Military status: Finished

Software Engineer with more than **9 years** experience in all phases of software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design and software testing mainly in backend **PHP**, **MySql**, **Laravel**.

Also can work as Full stack with HTML5-CSS5-JavaScript – Bootstrap – Gulp Js

I would like to work in an environment that provides opportunities for professional development, and enables to learn more about dealing with difficult and critical situations.

WORK EXPERIENCE IVAS

Jun 2018 until Now

Team Lead

- Lead the Development team.
- Review code to make sure that matching best practices, name convention.
- Support team in complicated tasks
- Make a deep and full testing for all new projects
- Handle recruitment
- Good background in Linux development and administration.
- Sending regular updates about projects status
- Building reusable code and libraries for future use.

Skills: Laravel – MySQL- PHP - Object Oriented Programming (OOP) - SOLID Design Principles - Software Design Patterns - Docker - Microservices - JavaScript - RabbitMQ - GraphQL – Redis - Debugging with PHP - Vue Js

iVASJun 2016 to Dec 2017

Senior Software Engineer

- Participates in all phases of software development cycle, business requirement analysis, software design and software testing.
- work on "VAS" value added service for web apps and mobile apps like call tones "rbts" and web push contents.

- Designs and develops relational database systems and their web interfaces.
- Provide written status reports & documentation for end users.
- Produce detailed specifications.
- Drawing up test strategies, stories, and test cases to test applications.
- Resolve technical issues through debugging, research and investigation.
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the core product software and databases to ensure strong optimization and functionality.
- Follow industry best practices.
- Develop and deploy new features to facilitate related procedures and tools if necessary.
- Ensure the quality of the developed applications.
- Write clean, well designed code.
- Developing applications using laravel framework.
- Maintain and fix problems for old projects.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – Laravel - Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) - JavaScript - Bootstrap – CSS3 – HTML5 - SASS - jQuery - Google Maps

SadaCode

Jun 2015 to Dec 2015

Senior PHP Developer

• Developing web applications using CakePHP framework.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – CakePHP

Edigits

Jan 2014 to Dec 2014

Senior PHP Developer

• Developing web applications using Laravel framework and Wordpress CMS.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – Laravel- WordPress - JavaScript

UKprosolutions Jan 2013 to Dec 2013

PHP Web Developer

• Developing web applications using YII framework.

Skills: PHP – MySQL – YII- Javascript -HTML- CSS

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science: Faculty of Engineering in Shoubra

• Grade: Very Good

SKILLS

• Experience With:

PHP - MySQL - Laravel - OOP - Design patterns - Solid Principles - MVC
RESTful SOAP Apis - GIT - Graph QL - Docker - Redis - Google Maps - HTML - HTML5 - CSS - CSS3 - JavaScript - ESC6 - Bootstrap - jQuery - jQuery Ui - AJAX - JSON - YII framework - Cakephp framework - Codeignitor framework

• Basic Of:

MicroServices - Rabbit MQ & Queue & Events - GitHub Actions – XML - RSS - SASS - familiar with linux - Vue JS – React Js - Node js - No Sql (Mongo) - CMS like wordpress

LANGUAGE

Arabic English Naive Very Good

PROJECTS

Aghezty

https://aghezty.com

Ecommerce website that user can register and login by his account Then make order by 3 available types (\cosh / Visa nbe / Visa CIB) and It contains a wonderful filter through which you can search by price range , brand filter , category filter and there is a dashboard to complete control all items on the website

✓ **Technologies**: PHP - Laravel - bootstrap - SASS - Checkout js integration for CIB and NBE

Greetings

https://greeting.digizone.com.kw/v1

Entertainment web app that enable user to:

- 1- Cut the video
- 2- Cut the audio
- 3- Merge an image and audio to generate a video
- 4- Merge multiple image to generate a vide
- 5- Make animation on the generated video
- 6- Write on the image
- 7- Write on the video
- 8- Make water marke on the video

✓Technologies: PHP - Laravel – bootstrap - Vue Js - FFMPEG